Princeton Ethiopic Manuscripts, late 1600s-1900s: Finding Aid C0776
Manuscripts Division
- Princeton Ethiopic Manuscript No. 19: Prayer against the Tongue (Ləsanä Säb'ə), 1800s; 19; 29 folios 1 col., 8 or 10 lines. Parchment Codex. Written in black and red ink. Two long strips of vellum, total length 115.5 cm, folded like a concertina, with 29 folios of 4 x 5.5 cm each. Three miniatures. Leather case, segmented in two to fit over each end of manuscripts, amulet style. Leather covers sewn to the ends of the strips. Blank folios at end and the beginning 4 x 5.5 cm (Unitid 19)
  Illustration: Three crosses, each taking up a page.
  Illustration: One häräg near beginning.
  Owner's name Gäbrä Mäsqäl Zälälä listed near the beginning of the manuscript.
  References: See S. Grebaut, " L'hymne-invocation lesana sab'e," Aethiopica 3 (1935): 6-12; Chaîne, "Répertoire," no. 314; Encyclopedia Aethiopica, vol. 3, 553-554.
- Princeton Ethiopic Manuscript No. 20: Miracles of Mary (Tä'amrä Maryam), Book of Baptism (Mäsəhafä Təmqät), 1700s; 20; 92 folios 2 cols. [fols. 1r-21r], 18 lines; [22r-91v], 20 lines. Parchment Codex. Written in black and red ink. No case. Glossy wooden boards, upper board broken and sewn, stitched and open spine. Loose binding. The folios of both manuscripts have been bound out of order and some folios are missing. 15.5 x 18.5 cm (Unitid 20)
  Fol. 21v: Pen trial in crude hand with black ink and pencil scrawl.
  Fols. 91v: The scribe's name is mentioned in the original manuscript but someone has erased it.
  Fols. 91v-92r: In another, later hand, is a note of the gift of the manuscript to a church (whose name has been erased).
  Fols. 92r: Ge'ez alphabet.
  Fols. 92v: Pen and pencil scrawls. Also throughout.
  Two manuscripts have been bound together, one is older than the other. They are in different hands. The first manuscript is the Book of Baptism, Miracles of St Michael, Miracles of Jesus, and Miracles of Mary. After fol. 22r are only Miracles of Mary.
  Gift of John Mason.
  Original owner: Kəflä Mika'e.
  Loose slip of paper noting cataloging information about the manuscript and a photocopy of part of a letter from John Mason, the purchaser, re. cataloging by Isaac Welde-Iesus in Kenya, dated to 1986.
  References: Regarding Miracles of Mary, see manuscript no. 8. Regarding Book of Baptism, see Sylvain Grébaut, "Ordre du Baptême et de la Confirmation dans l'Église Éthiopienne," ROC, vol. 26 (1927-8), pp. 105-89; Ernst Trumpp, "Das Taufebuch der aethiopischen Kircher: Aethiopisch und Deutsch," Abhandlungen der philosophisch.- philologischen Classe der Königlichen Bayerischen Akademie der Wissenschaften, vol.14, no. 111 (1878), pp. 147-83; Enclyopedia Aethiopica, vol. 1, pp. 468-470.
  - Miracles of Mary 1-10, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 1r-21r. (Unitid 20)
    The owner's name is not mentioned in this one of the two texts.
    - First Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 1rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary appeared with saints Abba Mäqars, Abba Yohannəs Abba Bəsoy, Abba Musse, Abba Yohannəs at the monastry of Asqetəs.
    - Second Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 1v-2r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary healed a woman at Bethlehem.
    - Third Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 2rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary left her handprint in the icon of the Virgin Mary when a certain priest burned incense and bowed to her icon and how she brought holy water inside the church and how Elarəya, daughter of King Zänun, left for the monastic life at Asqetəs (repeated later).
    - Homily of King Zärə'a Ya'əqob on the Honor of Virgin Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 2v-3r. (Unitid 20)
    - Fourth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 3v-4r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved the painter when he fell down from his scaffolding (different version of Budge, Mary, 8).
    - Fifth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 4rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary appeared to King Anorewos and how she led him to the ascetic life.
    - Sixth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 5rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved the robber's soul from judgment because he drank from water that sprang from her feet.
    - Seventh Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 5v-6r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary appeared to a certain ascetic woman to reassure her about the purity of her friends, other ascetics in the monastery (similar to twenty-second miracle later in this manuscript).
    - Eighth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 6rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary rebuked a woman when she gave up fasting at her husband's command (incomplete at the end) (Budge, Mary, 99).
    - Ninth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 9rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved a drunken monk from a lion (Budge, Mary, 48).
    - Tenth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 9v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary helped Säwla, wife of Giyorgis (the new martyr) when she wanted to bury the remain of her husband's body (incomplete at the end, folios including the end missing).
    - Prayer to Mary About the Reading of the Miracles, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 17r-19v. (Unitid 20)
  - Miracles of Mary 11-94, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 22r-91v. (Unitid 20)
    The original owner's name, Kəflä Mika'e, is mentioned in this text at the beginning of most of the miracles. The later owner has erased the original owner's name in the first few folios. But the name of Säga Mika'el, the father of Kəflä Mika'e, which also appears at the beginning of some miracles has escaped the eraser because his name is in black ink not red. Some other names sometimes appear at the beginning of the miracles, but those mentioned above are the most common.
    - Eleventh Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 22r-23v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary accepted the book of her miracles compiled by Saint Hildefonsus [Däqsəyos], Bishop of Toledo (Budge, Mary 1; Strelcyn 15.1.1, 32.16.1).
    - Twelfth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 23v-24r. (Unitid 20)
      How Jesus Christ asked the Virgin Mary about her five lamentations.
    - Thirteenth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 24v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved a certain adulterous person from his temptation in Alexandria (incomplete at the end, folios including the end missing from manuscript).
    - Fourteenth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 25r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary helped a young impoverished man and how the church keeper gave his daughter to him (incomplete at the beginning, which is at 72rv).
    - Fifteenth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 25v-26v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary appeared to a certain wealthy woman who was the patron of a monastery.
    - Sixteenth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 26r-27v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary appeared to the Färäsawi when he denied Christ but kept his devotion to the Virgin Mary.
    - Seventeenth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 27r-28v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved from the hand of a demon a monk who fell in love with a certain woman and drowned while going to visit her (Budge, Mary, 69).
    - Eighteenth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 28r-29v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved a certain nun who died before she finished her penitence and how she appeared to the Abbess and told her how the Virgin Mary saved her (similar to Romances, Cleopatra 13?).
    - Nineteenth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 29rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary helped a certain nun by encouraging her to pray Hail Mary everywhere.
    - Twentieth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 29v-30v. (Unitid 20)
      How the icon of the Virgin Mary bled when a certain Jew cast it to the ground (Budge, Mary, 68).
    - Twenty-First Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 30v. (Unitid 20)
      Excerpt, unclear, probably how the Virgin Mary appeared at Däbrä Metmaq.
    - Twenty-Second Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 31r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary appeared to the ascetic woman Arsema to reassure her about the purity of her friends, also at the monastery (incomplete at the beginning, which is at 75r).
    - Twenty-Third Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 31r-32r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved a noble man named Armatəyas in Ephesus from hanging when he was falsely accused.
    - Twenty-Fourth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 32r-33v. (Unitid 20)
      How the icon of the Virgin Mary at the Däbrä Qälmon monastery healed an Arab woman with hemorrhage.
    - Twenty-Fifth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 33v-35v. (Unitid 20)
      How a certain nun fled with a certain monk and how the Virgin Mary fulfilled the duties of the nun during her absence (Budge, Mary, 106).
    - Twenty-Sixth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 35v-37r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved a young man whose mother had promised him to the Devil (Budge, Mary, 49).
    - Twenty-Seventh Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 37r-39r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary delivered a certain Jew from a fiery furnace into which his father had cast him (Budge, Mary, 59).
    - Twenty-Eighth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 39r-40r. (Unitid 20)
      How Sybil the prophetess saw the Virgin Mary with Christ the Child inside the sun disk and revealed it to a king who did not want to be worshipped.
    - Twenty-Ninth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 40r-41v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary obtained forgiveness for a monk named Hərnay who had mutilated himself and died under the influence of Satan in disguise as a saint Mar Ya'əqob [Jacob] (Budge, Mary 101).
    - Thirtieth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 41v-42r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary spoke from her picture to a devout worshipper (Budge, Mary 2; Strelcyn 15.1.3, 32.16.2).
    - Thirty-First Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 42r-43r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary healed the elderly Jew of Akəmim when he fell and broke his back during the church service because of his old age (Budge, Mary, 3).
    - Thirty-Second Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 43r-44r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary appeared to the dying scribe Damianus of Philippi (Budge, Mary, 4).
    - Thirty-Third Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 44r-45r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary appeared to Isaac, the monk, and promised to take him to herself after three days (Budge, Mary, 6).
    - Thirty-Fourth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 45r-46r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary appeared out of her picture to Mary, the daughter of a certain God-fearing man, and promised to take her to Paradise after three days (Budge, Mary, 7).
    - Thirty-Fifth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 46r-47r. (Unitid 20)
      How a painter was saved by the Virgin Mary when he fell from a scaffold (Budge, Mary, 8).
    - Thirty-Sixth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 47r-48r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary carried a sick person from the Monastery of the Pilgrims to Jerusalem and showed him where Jesus was crucified and buried and baptized him in the waters of the Jordan (Budge, Mary, 9).
    - Thirty-Seventh Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 48rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary recovered the stolen property of two women called Juliana and Barbara, when they were on pilgrimage to Jerusalem (Budge, Mary, 11; Strelcyn 32.16. 11).
    - Thirty-Eighth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 48v-49v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary moved the Monastery in Greece to Jericho road (Budge, Mary, 13; Strelcyn 32.16. 13).
    - Thirty-Ninth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 49v-50v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary healed the merchant from Colossae after being shot in the eye with an arrow by pirates (Budge, Mary, 15; Strelcyn 32.16. 15).
    - Fortieth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 50v-51v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary arranged marriages for two poor girls called Martha and Yäwahit (Budge, Mary, 17; Strelcyn 32.16. 17).
    - Forty-First Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 51v-52v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary delivered the soul of the scribe who was writing the book of her miracles when the demons took him by mistake to hell (Budge, Mary, 18; Strelcyn 32.16.18).
    - Forty-Second Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 52v-53r. (Unitid 20)
      How the icon of the Virgin Mary spoke to a certain woman whose mother-in-law was opposed to her devotion to the icon of the Virgin and how the icon disappeared because of the mother-in-law's objection.
    - Forty-Third Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 53rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary delivered from prison a certain man called Giyorgis the New Martyr (Budge, Mary, 19; Strelcyn 32.16. 19).
    - Fragment of a Miracle About a Certain Priest, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 53v. (Unitid 20)
    - Forty-Fourth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 54r-55r. (Unitid 20)
      How a certain rich man called Paqlima hurled a loaf at the head of a beggar and wounded him, and how the Virgin Mary delivered his soul from demons (Budge, Mary, 86).
    - Forty-Fifth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 55rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary helped a certain wealthy women from Caesarea to give birth to a child when her relatives brought her to the Icon of the Virgin Mary.
    - Forty-Sixth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 55v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary healed the foot of a widow from Harətärom (incomplete at the end) (Budge, Mary, 24).
    - Forty-Seventh Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 56rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary appeared to a certain shepherd and promised to take him to herself in paradise and how she lead him to a certain monastery to die there (incomplete at the end, folio flipped, continues on 60v).
    - Forty-Eighth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 57rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Icon of the Virgin Mary spoke to a certain woman who swallowed scorpion when she was depressed and how the voice from the icon led her to a certain wise man for her healing (incomplete at the beginning).
    - Forty-Ninth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 57v-58vr. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved the people on a certain ship on the sea when they were caught in a powerful storm.
    - Fiftieth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 58v-59v and 61rv. (Unitid 20)
      How a certain young man placed a ring on the finger of a icon of the Virgin Mary and how the virgin regarded it as an engagement ring) (incomplete at the end, which appears on 61rv (Budge, Mary, 67).
    - Fifty-First Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 60rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary sent the shepherd to the monastery and how he died after he blessed the monks in the monastery (incomplete at the beginning, a continuation of fol. 56v).
    - Fifty-Second Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 61v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary helped a certain church whose leader had died very recently (excerpt).
    - Fifty-Third Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 62rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved a certain evil wealthy man's soul from demons and how she took him in to paradise.
    - Fifty-Fourth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 62v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved the soul of a wicked monastic leader after he died because he was devoted to her and how he appeared to his disciple and told him how she saved him from hell (incomplete at the end, which is at 64rv).
    - Fifty-Fifth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 63rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary healed a man with a stone foot (Budge, Mary, 22; Strelcyn 32.16.22) (incomplete at the end).
    - Fifty-Sixth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 64rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved the soul of certain monk after he died (incomplete at the beginning, which is at 61v).
    - Fifty-Seventh Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 64v. (Unitid 20)
      Four-line fragment, does not continue on 65r.
    - Fifty-Eighth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 65r. (Unitid 20)
      Fragment, does not continue from 64v.
    - Fifty-Ninth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 65r-66r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved the thief from hanging.
    - Sixtieth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 66rv. (Unitid 20)
      (How the Virgin Mary appeared in the monastery of Asqetəs with the church fathers.
    - Sixty-First Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 66r-68r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary brought water to the well of Däbrä Mətmaq.
    - Sixty-Second Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 68r-69v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary appeared to Deacon Yohannəs in the Pillar of Light.
    - Sixty-Third Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 70r-71r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary appeared to Yohannəs Käma and how she commanded him to build a church.
    - Sixty-Fourth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 71r-72r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary punished the son of the king of the Egypt when he challenged the Virgin Mary and Jesus Christ.
    - Sixty-Fifth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 72rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary helped a young impoverished man and how the church keeper gave his daughter to him (incomplete, the end of the story is at 25r).
    - Sixty-Sixth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 73rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the icon of the Virgin Mary exuded oil and milk (incomplete at the beginning) (Budge, Mary, 59).
    - Sixty-Seventh Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 73v-74v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary raised a dead martyred knight to fight against an enemy of the church called Goliath (Goləyəd) (Budge, Mary, 60).
    - Sixty-Eighth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 75r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary left her handprint in the icon of the Virgin Mary when a certain priest burned incense and bowed to her icon and how she brought holy water inside the church and how Elarəya, daughter of King Zänun, left for the monastic life at Asqetəs (fragment).
    - Sixty-Ninth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 75rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary appeared to an ascetic woman named Arsema to reassure her about the purity of her friends, also at the monastery (incomplete at the end, the end is at 31r) (repeated).
    - Seventieth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 76rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary raised from the dead a certain man's son (incomplete at the beginning).
    - Seventy-First Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 76v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary helped a wicked prince who was devoted to the Virgin Mary but became mad (incomplete at the end, see 79rv for end).
    - Seventy-Second Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 77rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved the soul of a young man who denied God and the angels but kept his faith in the Virgin Mary (excerpt).
    - Seventy-Third Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 78rv. (Unitid 20)
      How a certain Jew of Constantinople threw to the ground a picture of the Virgin Mary and when it was restored it exuded oil that healed many (Budge, Mary, 45).
    - Seventy-Fourth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 79rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary wicked prince who was devoted to the Virgin Mary but became mad (incomplete at the beginning, see 76r for beginning).
    - Seventy-Fifth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 79v-80r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary gave children to a certain woman whose nine children had died when the woman promised that they would become priests and deacons.
    - Seventy-Sixth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 80r-81r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary received the soul of Barok, a dissolute man (Budge, Mary, 26).
    - Seventy-Seventh Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 81rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary received the soul of Anəsətasəyos of Rome (Budge, Mary, 27).
    - Seventy-Eighth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 81v-82r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary helped a monk to escape the monastery of Qäləmon when persecuted by other monks when he breached the wall of the church by hitting it with his skull cap (Budge, Mary, 28; Strelcyn 32.16.28).
    - Seventy-Ninth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 82rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved a thief from his persecutors.
    - Eightieth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 82v-83r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved the woman in childbirth from drowning (Budge, Mary, 32; Strelcyn 32.16. 31; Bland 2, also Vincent de Beauvais).
    - Eighty-First Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 83r-84r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary gave water to a thirsty dog (Budge, Mary, 33; Strelcyn 32.16. 32).
    - Eighty-Second Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 84r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary gave a garment to a monk (Budge, Mary, 93).
    - Eighty-Third Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 84r-85r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary begged her son to forgive the sins of a wealthy evil man.
    - Eighty-Fourth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 85rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary appeared before a certain woman in the monastery during church service.
    - Eighty-Fifth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 85v-86v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary anointed the animal's feet while she was at Däbrä Qusəqam, according to Saint Anthony.
    - Eighty-Sixth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 86v-87r. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary appeared at Däbrä Qusəqam, according to Saint Anthony.
    - Eighty-Seventh Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 87rv. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary saved Timothy, a drunken monk, from a lion) (Budge, Mary, 48).
    - Eighty-Eighth Miracle of Mary, 1700s; multiple folios; Located on folio 87v. (Unitid 20)
      How the Virgin Mary performed a miracle on her feast day at Wäme[?] (excerpt).